Guide to the Black Action Society Files, 1968-1992 UA.55.13.3
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Black Action Society Files
1968-1992
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Black Action Society
UA.55.13.3
1.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Includes minutes, publications and subject files of the Black Action Society of the University of Pittsburgh from 1968-1998.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Mrs. Teresa McCray in 1998.
Previous Citation
Black Action Society Files, 1968-1992, UA.55.13.3, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
Minutes, publications and subject files of the Black Action Society of the University of Pittsburgh from 1968-1998.
History
In May of 1968 a group of African American students formed an organization that would address the needs and concerns of the African American student community at the University of Pittsburgh. Among their demands was that the University actively recruit and admit black students, that the role of African Americans in the history of this and other countries be incorporated into the curricula of Pitt's courses, that the number of black faculty be increased, and that a Black Studies Program be developed within the University. This collection consists of the minutes of this organization from 1968 to 1989.
University of Pittsburgh; Ethnic groups -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; African American college students -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Societies and clubs; University of Pittsburgh. Black Action Society; University of Pittsburgh -- Students -- Societies, etc.
- Minutes, 1968-1992; I.
  - Minutes, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Job Fair/Resume Books, 1985-1998; II.
  - Book, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Book, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Book, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Book, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Book, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Book, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Book, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Book, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Book, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Periodicals, 1968-1995; III.
  - BAS News, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - BAS News, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - BAS News, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - BAS News, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - BAS News, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - BAS News, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - BAS Network, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 26a)
  - BAS Forum, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Blacklines, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Blacklines, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Subject Files, 1969-1980; IV.
  - Art work, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Awards/Certificates, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - BAS-Student Government Board Relations, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Black Paper for Black Studies, June 1, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Drug Abuse Center, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Early Childhood Education Center, Proposal by Barbara L. Hayden, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Event flyers, tickets, and programs, 1968-1979 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - National Black Nurses' Association, Inc., Conference, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Organization of Black Administrators, Faculty, Staff and Students of the University of Pittsburgh, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Steering Committee, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Swahili in Afro-America by Sanza Clark, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Trial of Bobby Seale: The Conspiracy, The New York Review, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - University News Releases and Proposals, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - FASC Racism Seminar, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- 2020 Addition, V.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series includes Black Action Society publications that were utilized in the 40th and 50th anniversary celebrations of the BAS. Also included is a draft constitution of the Afro-American Cultural Society, which was the predecessor organization of the BAS.
  - Afro-American Cultural Society Constitution (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Black Student Handbook, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Computer Center Sit-in Subject File, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "The Black Action Society and the Computer Center Incident," by Joseph P. McCormick, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - As-Salaam-Alaikum, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Black Students Seize the Power to Define," by Bebe Moore and Martha Carson, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Things to Know about the Black Community of Pittsburgh", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters and Event Programs, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    These items were donated to the archives by Pamela E. Heywood and used in the 2018 African American Alumni Council Black Action Society exhibit.
  - Blackline, 2010-2016 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    These items were donated to the archives by Karee Rogers and used in the 2018 African American Alumni Council Black Action Society exhibit.